So, now let's talk about prompt engineering.
So, what is prompt engineering?
Well, say we have a knife prompt, for example,
summarize what is AWS.
And we submit this prompt to our LLM.
So, this prompt is okay.
We're going to get an answer from an LLM,
but is it the answer we really want?
So, prompting this type of prompt will give little guidance
and leaves a lot to the model interpretation.
So, we can do prompt engineering.
That means we're going to develop design
and optimize these kind of prompts
to make sure that the foundation model
have output will fit our need.
So, to have an improved prompt technique,
we have four blocks.
The first one is the instructions.
So, what is the task for the model to do?
For example, we're going to describe
how the model should perform the task.
Then context, what is external information
to guide the model?
Then we have input data.
So, what is the data for which we want a response?
And finally, an output indicator.
What is the type or the format of the output that we want?
And all these things together is going to give us
a much better prompt and a much better answer.
So, here is a concrete example
where we are going to improve our nice prompt.
So, here I'm going to provide instructions.
And instead of knowing what AWS is,
we want to write a concise summary
that captures the main points of an article
about learning AWS.
And we need to ensure that the summary is clear
and informative, focusing on key services,
and you can read the rest and so on.
So, this is some very detailed instructions
because we're very clear about what we want.
Then we have some context.
So, I am actually teaching a beginners course
on AWS.
And so, therefore, the model will respond in a way
that it can be understood by beginners.
Then we can give some input data.
So, here is some input data about AWS.
And this is what I want the foundation model
to summarize.
And finally, the output indicator.
So, I want you to provide,
I want the FM to provide a two, three sentence summary
that will capture the essence of the article.
So, here, this is great because I'm very clear,
I have provided very clear instructions,
good context, input data, and an output indicator.
And so, therefore, when I will use it on my LLM,
then I will get the expected output,
which are two to three sentences,
which summarize what is AWS based on this article
from a beginner's context.
So, hopefully, that makes sense.
And this is something that AWS wants you to know.
Next, we have the technique called negative prompting.
So, this is a technique where we explicitly instruct the model
on what not to include or to do in its response.
So, when you have negative prompting,
it helps to avoid unwanted contents.
So, we specify explicitly what we don't want.
And therefore, we reduce the chances of irrelevant
or inappropriate contents.
And we maintain the focus.
We make sure that the prompt and the model
will stay on the topic.
Then we have enhanced clarity,
because, well, for example, we can say,
don't use complex terminology or don't use detail data
so we can make the output clearer and so on.
So, let's have a look at this enhanced prompting
before, but now we're going to add on negative prompting.
So, now the instructions are going to be exactly the same,
but instead, I'm going to say,
avoid discussing technical configurations,
specific AWS tutorials or personal learning experiences.
The context will say the same,
the inputs data will stay the same.
And for the output indicator,
I'm going to say do not include technical terms
in depth data analysis or speculation.
And so, I'm not going to show you what the output of this
is because there's no points,
but as you can see, by adding negative prompting,
we are even more clear about what we want
and what we don't want in an output from an LLM.
So, that's it for this lecture on prompt engineering.
I suggest that you try a little bit on your own
to see where you can and cannot get out of this technique.
And I hope you liked it.
I will see you in the next lecture.